Finding Aid for Greater Lansing Urban League records, 1964-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Greater Lansing Urban League records 1964-1976
Greater Lansing Urban League.
2 linear feet
85203 Bd 2
Affiliate chapter of the National Urban League. Annual reports, minutes of board of directors, and subject files concerning the work of the league in matters of employment and other community services; also speeches and other files of Charles H. Mitchner, executive director.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the chapter (donor no. 6078 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Greater Lansing Urban League is a chapter of the National Urban League. The chapter is involved in such issues as employment, housing, and other welfare concerns.
The Greated Lanasing Urban League reocrds have been arranged into two series: Organizational Records and Programs and Topical Files. The Organizational records series consists of the minutes of the board of directors, audits, and annual and other reports. The Programs series includes files on the different activities of the League in matters of jobs, education and housing. This series also includes speeches and other files of Charles H. Mitchner, executive director of the League chapter.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan.; Lansing (Mich.).; National Urban League.; Greater Lansing Urban League.; Mitchner, Charles H.
- Organizational Records
  - By-laws and revisions (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Board of Directors and supplementary papers
    - 1964-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - January-February 1973 (Box 1)
    - March-April 1973 (Box 1)
    - May-June 1973 (Box 1)
    - September-October 1973 (Box 1)
    - November-December 1973 (Box 1)
    - January 1974 (Box 1)
    - February-March 1974 (Box 1)
    - April-June 1974 (Box 1)
    - September-October 1974 (Box 1)
    - November-December 1974 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report
    - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971, 1972 and 1974 (Box 1)
  - Audits
    - 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Personnel policy statement (Box 1)
  - Quarterly reports and fact sheets, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly reports and fact sheets, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
- Programs and topical files
  - Minority Education Survey Program, 1975, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - National Urban League materials, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Calendars (Box 1)
  - Jackson County Outreach program, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Minority Health Service Proposal, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Proposal for Providing Service (Box 1)
  - Consumer Health, Education and Training Program (Box 1)
  - Leadership Development Program, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, "Outreach" (Box 1)
  - Management Training and Development Seminar, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Conference of Municipal officials, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Lansing Urban Renewal material (Box 2)
  - Speeches by executive director, Charles H. Mitchner (Box 2)
  - Employment materials, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Welfare (Box 2)
  - Lansing Family Health Center Project, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Project "Leap" (Box 2)
  - Assistant Regional Director for Governmental Affairs (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1969-1976 (Box 2)
  - National Urban League Black Student Summer Program Annual Report, 1971 (Box 2)
  - National Urban League Field Services New Thrust Proposal Summaries, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act Proposal, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Family Helpers Proposal, Lansing School District, February 1969 (Box 2)